<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录</title><link/>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R<description>拉曼光谱杂志目录。最新期和 EarlyView 期的文章列表。</description><language> en-US</language><copyright> © 约翰·威利父子有限公司</copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（Wiley 在线图书馆）</managingeditor><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 21:37:44 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 10 月 9 日星期一 21:37:44 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>拉曼光谱杂志</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录</title><url>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/10974555.jpg</url><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R<item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6602?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 02:54:14 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-10-05T02:54:14-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6602</guid><title>拉曼光谱作为监测绝经后骨质疏松症治疗骨质疏松症的工具</title><description>拉曼光谱学杂志，EarlyView。</description><dc:description>骨活性药物系统地影响人类的角蛋白结构。基于人类指甲拉曼光谱的模型可以区分经过治疗和未经治疗的个体。模型与先前的骨质疏松症模型相关。随着时间的推移，未经治疗的个体表现出骨质疏松风险增加的趋势，而接受治疗的个体则表现出逆转，表明风险降低。摘要 基于双膦酸盐的骨质疏松症药物治疗可降低骨折风险，但骨矿物质密度的调节并不能单独解释这一点。需要更好地了解影响脆性的其他骨质量方面以及监测它们的方法。影响骨胶原重塑的全身因素也会同时重塑角蛋白。在这项研究中，对接受和不接受骨活性药物干预的受试者的人类指甲剪进行了比较。判别模型能够区分指甲与未接受过治疗以及测试集中曲线下面积为 71% 的患者的指甲。相对于基线的时间序列变化显示，1 年后，治疗组的分数（95 置信区间 37% 至 377% 变化）与 12 周测量值（−198% 至 34%）和未治疗组的分数不同受试者（−92％至−674％）。对光谱差异和模型系数的分析揭示了与之前三个骨质疏松症模型中观察到的相反的特征，表明治疗正在恢复受损的蛋白质结构。这项研究提供了初步证据，表明骨活性药物系统地影响人类角蛋白结构，并对其潜在机制进行了一些讨论。该研究表明双膦酸盐对蛋白质结构有直接影响，值得进一步研究这些影响。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/60d22f5b-5db9-4cb2-b3e7-9db960625f67/jrs6602-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;拉曼光谱作为一种工具监测绝经后骨质疏松症的骨质疏松症治疗”/>; &lt;p>;骨活性药物系统性地影响人类的角蛋白结构。基于人类指甲拉曼光谱的模型可以区分经过治疗和未经治疗的个体。模型与先前的骨质疏松症模型相关。随着时间的推移，未经治疗的个体表现出骨质疏松风险增加的趋势，而接受治疗的个体则表现出逆转，表明风险降低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;基于双膦酸盐的骨质疏松症药物治疗可降低骨折风险，但骨矿物质密度的调节并不能单独解释这一点。需要更好地了解影响脆性的其他骨质量方面以及监测它们的方法。影响骨胶原重塑的全身因素也会同时重塑角蛋白。在这项研究中，对接受和不接受骨活性药物干预的受试者的人类指甲剪进行了比较。判别模型能够区分指甲与未接受过治疗且接受测试集中曲线下面积为 71% 的患者的指甲。相对于基线的时间序列变化显示，1 年后，治疗组的分数（95 置信区间 37% 至 377% 变化）与 12 周测量值（−198% 至 34%）和未治疗组的分数不同受试者（−92％至−674％）。对光谱差异和模型系数的分析揭示了与之前三个骨质疏松症模型中观察到的相反的特征，表明治疗正在恢复受损的蛋白质结构。这项研究提供了初步证据，表明骨活性药物系统地影响人类角蛋白结构，并对其潜在机制进行了一些讨论。研究表明，双膦酸盐对蛋白质结构有直接影响，值得进一步研究这些影响。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> J.伦维克·贝蒂、马克·R.托勒</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>拉曼光谱作为监测绝经后骨质疏松症治疗骨质疏松症的工具</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1002/jrs.6602</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>拉曼光谱杂志</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1002/jrs.6602</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6602?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6604?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 04:54:21 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-10-03T04:54:21-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6604</guid><title>洞察纯 P3HT 器件中极化子对动力学的光和静电场诱导偏振：一项基于瞬态吸收光谱的研究</title><description>拉曼光谱学杂志，EarlyView。</description><dc:description>研究了纯 P3HT 薄膜和纯 P3HT 二极管的振动热激子态激发后的极化子对动力学。我们证明了 p 偏振激发光的入射角以及二极管器件的内部和外部电场都会影响动力学。系统地研究了场致解离以及光和电场引起的偏振效应。摘要：我们研究了有机半导体光电器件中振动热激子态激发后的极化子对动力学，以更好地了解光物理性质，这有助于提高器件性能。在我们早期的工作中，发表在“Phys”上。化学。化学。 Phys., 2019,21, 21236-21248&#39;，我们研究了纯聚（3-己基噻吩-2,5-二基）器件中静电​​内部和外部场对极化子对动力学的作用。由此，我们得出结论，由于器件内部存在内部场，极化子对解离成电荷载流子，并且当在反向偏压下施加外部电场时，解离过程会加速。除了电场诱导的解离过程之外，我们现在还对光和电场诱导的极化效应对极化子对动力学的影响感兴趣。为此，在本研究中，我们使用飞秒瞬态吸收光谱来研究基于 P3HT 的器件中不同光入射角以及静电场附加变化的极化子对动力学。众所周知，薄膜光伏器件可以设计用于改善特定角度下的角度依赖性响应度，并且光子收集效率取决于光的入射角。内部电场和入射光电场都会影响器件的电荷生成效率，这是由电子激发和电荷形成之间发生的光物理过程决定的。正如我们的研究所证明的那样，由于入射角的变化和电场诱发极化的影响而引起的反射率的变化对极化子对动力学产生了总体影响。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/151cd5ae-c4a8-4829-bf52-e63d45e20282/jrs6604-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;洞察光和静态-纯 P3HT 器件中极化子对动力学的电场诱导极化：基于瞬态吸收光谱的研究&quot;/>; &lt;p>;纯 P3HT 薄膜的振动热激子态激发后的极化子对动力学和仅 P3HT 二极管已被研究。我们证明了 p 偏振激发光的入射角以及二极管器件的内部和外部电场都会影响动力学。系统地研究了场致解离以及光和电场致极化效应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们研究了有机半导体光电器件中振动热激子态激发后的极化子对动力学，以更好地了解其光物理性质，可以帮助提高设备性能。在我们早期的工作中，发表在 &#39;&lt;i>;Phys.化学。化学。 Phys&lt;/i>;., 2019,21, 21236-21248&#39;，我们研究了纯聚（3-己基噻吩-2,5-二基）中静电内部和外部场对极化子对动力学的作用基于设备。由此，我们得出结论，由于器件内部存在内部场，极化子对解离成电荷载流子，并且当在反向偏压下也施加外部电场时，解离过程会加速。除了电场诱导的解离过程之外，我们现在还对光和电场诱导的极化效应对极化子对动力学的影响感兴趣。为此，在本研究中，我们使用飞秒瞬态吸收光谱来研究基于 P3HT 的纯器件中不同光入射角以及静电场附加变化的极化子对动力学。众所周知，薄膜光伏器件可以设计用于改善特定角度下的角度相关响应度，并且光子收集效率取决于光的入射角。内部电场和入射光电场都会影响器件的电荷生成效率，这是由电子激发和电荷形成之间发生的光物理过程决定的。我们的研究表明，入射角变化引起的反射率变化以及电场诱发极化的影响对极化子对动力学产生整体影响。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>德布库玛·拉纳、阿努尔夫·马特尼</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>洞察纯 P3HT 器件中极化子对动力学的光和静电场诱导偏振：一项基于瞬态吸收光谱的研究</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1002/jrs.6604</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>拉曼光谱杂志</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1002/jrs.6604</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6604?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6579?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6579</guid><title>使用宽带光纤激光源对相干拉曼散射光谱中的光谱覆盖范围和光谱分辨率进行数值评估</title><description>《拉曼光谱杂志》，第 54 卷，第 9 期，第 1001-1010 页，2023 年 9 月。</description><dc:description>使用数值模拟工具使我们能够评估 CRS 光谱的光谱分辨率和光谱覆盖范围。本文介绍了使用全光纤激光源在 C-H 窗口和指纹区域进行高分辨率 CRS 光谱的初步结果。该仿真工具可以容纳任意形状的光脉冲，是一种用户友好且多功能的开源软件。摘要：我们从理论上研究了使用光纤激光源进行高分辨率和宽带相干拉曼散射（CRS）光谱/成像（采用光谱聚焦技术）的可行性。为了完成这项任务，我们开发了一种模拟工具，可以使用分步傅里叶方法直接从任何脉冲传播软件导入激光脉冲参数，以评估 CRS 光谱的光谱分辨率和光谱覆盖范围。因此，该仿真工具可以容纳任意形状和中心波长的光脉冲，也是一个用户友好且多功能的开源软件。我们通过将其结果与已发表的理论和实验数据进行比较来验证数值模拟工具。然后，我们使用该工具研究使用全光纤激光源在 C-H 窗口和指纹区域进行高分辨率 CRS 光谱的可行性。该工具在 CRS 光谱学有用的多个领域具有广泛的应用，例如生物医学、材料表征和生物成像。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/6ea6577b-458f-424b-bcbf-148a95d6f74e/jrs6579-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;光谱覆盖范围的数值评估和使用宽带光纤激光源的相干拉曼散射光谱的光谱分辨率”/>; &lt;p>;使用数值模拟工具使我们能够评估 CRS 光谱的光谱分辨率和光谱覆盖范围。本文介绍了使用全光纤激光源在 CH 窗口和指纹区域进行高分辨率 CRS 光谱的初步结果。该仿真工具可以容纳任意形状的光脉冲，是一款用户友好且多功能的开源软件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们从理论上研究了使用光纤激光源采用光谱聚焦技术进行高分辨率和宽带相干拉曼散射（CRS）光谱/成像的可行性。为了完成这项任务，我们开发了一种模拟工具，可以使用分步傅里叶方法直接从任何脉冲传播软件导入激光脉冲参数，以评估 CRS 光谱的光谱分辨率和光谱覆盖范围。因此，该仿真工具可以容纳任意形状和中心波长的光脉冲，也是一个用户友好且多功能的开源软件。我们通过将其结果与已发表的理论和实验数据进行比较来验证数值模拟工具。然后，我们使用该工具研究在 CH 窗口和指纹区域使用全光纤激光源进行高分辨率 CRS 光谱的可行性。该工具在 CRS 光谱学有用的多个领域具有广泛的应用，例如生物医学、材料表征和生物成像。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>劳拉·蒙罗伊、约书亚·马格努斯、米格尔·冈萨雷斯·埃雷兹、费尔南多·B·纳兰霍、Khanh Kieu</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用宽带光纤激光源对相干拉曼散射光谱中的光谱覆盖范围和光谱分辨率进行数值评估</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1002/jrs.6579</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>拉曼光谱杂志</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1002/jrs.6579</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6579?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6580?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6580</guid><title>用于散射方向性和拉曼激发光谱高光谱成像的多模态显微镜系统</title><description>《拉曼光谱杂志》，第 54 卷，第 9 期，第 976-987 页，2023 年 9 月。</description><dc:description>提出了多模态拉曼显微系统的构建，该系统能够对拉曼散射和暗场散射的角分布以及拉曼激发剖面进行高光谱成像。通过研究沉积在金纳米棒上的孔雀石绿的表面增强拉曼散射，证明了该系统的功能。摘要 等离子体纳米结构能够实现电磁场的强局域化，这使得它们能够用于增强拉曼信号。这种特性在各个领域都有广泛的应用，从检测少量物质到研究化合物与金属之间的相互作用。尽管金属纳米粒子增强拉曼信号的一般机制已被接受，但由于其复杂性，与纳米粒子与分子相互作用有关的细节仍然无法解释。需要一种多功能、高分辨率的显微镜系统来研究纳米颗粒的光谱特性及其增强的拉曼信号。这项研究描述了一种多功能显微镜系统，旨在对化学功能化的等离子体纳米结构进行全面的显微光谱分析。该集成系统结合了各种激发和检测模式，可实现高光谱拉曼映射、瑞利（暗场）散射高光谱映射以及散焦模式下的角散射和发射映射。激发波数选择的灵活性确保了最佳测量效率以及根据激发执行所有测量的能力。我们使用沉积在金纳米棒上的孔雀石绿展示了该系统的功能，展示了表面增强拉曼散射（SERS）激发轮廓和使用拉曼散射技术角度分布的高光谱成像的散射方向性散焦成像。这种集成显微镜系统有望在单粒子水平上推进等离子体纳米结构及其与化合物相互作用的研究。提出了多模态拉曼显微系统的构建，该系统能够对拉曼散射和暗场散射的角分布以及拉曼激发剖面进行高光谱成像。通过研究沉积在金纳米棒上的孔雀石绿的表面增强拉曼散射，证明了该系统的功能。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/61f2bd92-bf20-4006-b3c6-e6acf528fe6b/jrs6580-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;用于高光谱成像的多模态显微镜系统散射方向性和拉曼激发光谱的研究”/>; &lt;p>;介绍了多模态拉曼显微系统的构建，该系统能够对拉曼散射和暗场散射的角分布以及拉曼激发剖面进行高光谱成像。通过研究沉积在金纳米棒上的孔雀石绿的表面增强拉曼散射，证明了该系统的功能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;等离激元纳米结构能够实现电磁场的强局域化，这使得它们能够用于增强拉曼信号。这种特性在各个领域都有广泛的应用，从检测少量物质到研究化合物与金属之间的相互作用。尽管金属纳米粒子增强拉曼信号的一般机制已被接受，但由于其复杂性，与纳米粒子与分子相互作用有关的细节仍然无法解释。需要一种多功能、高分辨率的显微镜系统来研究纳米颗粒的光谱特性以及由它们增强的拉曼信号。这项研究描述了一种多功能显微镜系统，旨在对化学功能化的等离子体纳米结构进行全面的显微光谱分析。该集成系统结合了各种激发和检测模式，可实现高光谱拉曼映射、瑞利（暗场）散射高光谱映射以及散焦模式下的角散射和发射映射。激发波数选择的灵活性确保了最佳测量效率以及根据激发执行所有测量的能力。我们使用沉积在金纳米棒上的孔雀石绿展示了系统的功能，展示了表面增强拉曼散射（SERS）激发轮廓和使用拉曼散射技术角度分布的高光谱成像的散射方向性散焦成像。这种集成显微镜系统有望在单粒子水平上推进等离子体纳米结构及其与化合物相互作用的研究。提出了多模态拉曼显微系统的构建，该系统能够对拉曼散射和暗场散射的角分布以及拉曼激发剖面进行高光谱成像。通过研究沉积在金纳米棒上的孔雀石绿的表面增强拉曼散射，证明了该系统的功能。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>阿卜杜尔瓦哈卜·阿米尔萨拉里、塞佩尔·拉齐、西尔维斯特·加温科斯基</dc:creator><category>特刊-研究文章</category><dc:title>用于散射方向性和拉曼激发光谱高光谱成像的多模态显微镜系统</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1002/jrs.6580</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>拉曼光谱杂志</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1002/jrs.6580</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6580?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>特刊-研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6519?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6519</guid><title>用于生物传感的近红外染料编码纳米标签：官能团对基于 SERRS 的 LFA 灵敏度和性能的作用</title><description>《拉曼光谱杂志》，第 54 卷，第 9 期，第 929-939 页，2023 年 9 月。</description><dc:description>我们使用我们自制的线聚焦照明阅读器，报告了五种花青染料中异硫氰酸酯 (ITC) 的积极作用和磺酸根 (SO) 基团对 NIR-SERRS-LFA 中纳米标签的灵敏度和性能的消极作用。摘要 表面增强共振拉曼散射（SERRS）基于支持局域表面等离子体共振以及分子吸附物电子共振的纳米结构。明亮的 NIR-SERRS 纳米标签需要在 NIR 激光激发下具有高拉曼散射截面的染料，并结合化学吸附的官能团。在这里，我们报告了五种花青染料中的异硫氰酸酯 (ITC) 和磺酸酯 (SO) 基团对基于 SERRS 的 LFA 中纳米标签的灵敏度和性能的作用。对裸金纳米星 (AuNS) 进行的染料浓度依赖性 SERRS 和 zeta 电位测量揭示了它们的灵敏度和稳定性与 ITC 和 SO 基团数量的函数存在显着差异。观察到由于更强的化学吸附而与 ITC 基团的数量呈正相关，并且由于较高的水溶性而导致更强的解吸而与 SO 基团的数量呈负相关。基于 SERRS 的生物传感应用需要额外的功能化步骤，例如 PEG 与 NIR 染料的共吸附。生物共轭前后拉曼强度的比较表明，无论是否额外存在 SO 基团，至少存在一个 ITC 基团对于最大限度地减少拉曼信号损失是必要的。在用于检测妊娠标志物 β-hCG 的基于 SERRS 的侧向层析测定 (LFA) 中，两种染料 NIR 4f 和 NIR 5e（ITC = 2，SO = 0）显示出最佳性能。相反，我们不建议使用 IR-783（ITC = 0，SO = 2）进行基于 SERRS 的生物传感。总的来说，这项研究强调了表面寻找部分（例如常见的 ITC 基团）对于基于 SERRS 的生物传感平台的最佳性能的重要性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/69b24170-c820-4885-9547-654832098afd/jrs6519-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;NIR 染料编码纳米标签生物传感：基于 SERRS 的 LFA 中官能团对灵敏度和性能的作用”/>; &lt;p>;我们报告了五种花青染料中异硫氰酸酯 (ITC) 的积极作用和磺酸根 (SO) 基团对灵敏度和性能的消极作用使用我们自制的具有线聚焦照明的读取器在 NIR-SERRS-LFA 中读取纳米标签。 &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;表面增强共振拉曼散射（SERRS）基于支持局域表面等离子体共振以及分子吸附物电子共振的纳米结构。明亮的 NIR-SERRS 纳米标签需要在 NIR 激光激发下具有高拉曼散射截面的染料，并结合化学吸附的官能团。在这里，我们报告了五种花青染料中的异硫氰酸酯 (ITC) 和磺酸酯 (SO) 基团对基于 SERRS 的 LFA 中纳米标签的灵敏度和性能的作用。对裸金纳米星 (AuNS) 进行的染料浓度依赖性 SERRS 和 zeta 电位测量揭示了它们的灵敏度和稳定性与 ITC 和 SO 基团数量的函数存在显着差异。观察到由于更强的化学吸附而与 ITC 基团的数量呈正相关，并且由于较高的水溶性而导致更强的解吸而与 SO 基团的数量呈负相关。基于 SERRS 的生物传感应用需要额外的功能化步骤，例如 PEG 与 NIR 染料的共吸附。生物共轭前后拉曼强度的比较表明，无论是否额外存在 SO 基团，至少存在一个 ITC 基团对于最大限度地减少拉曼信号损失是必要的。在用于检测妊娠标志物 β-hCG 的基于 SERRS 的侧向层析测定 (LFA) 中，两种染料 NIR 4f 和 NIR 5e（ITC = 2，SO = 0）显示出最佳性能。相反，我们不建议使用 IR-783（ITC = 0，SO = 2）进行基于 SERRS 的生物传感。总的来说，这项研究强调了表面寻找部分（例如常见的 ITC 基团）对于基于 SERRS 的生物传感平台的最佳性能的重要性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>崔南贤、Mujo Adanalic、阿森·丹科夫、罗兰·格热西克、米歇尔·赫克勒、塞巴斯蒂安·施吕克</dc:creator><category>特刊-研究文章</category><dc:title>用于生物传感的近红外染料编码纳米标签：官能团对基于 SERRS 的 LFA 灵敏度和性能的作用</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1002/jrs.6519</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>拉曼光谱杂志</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1002/jrs.6519</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6519?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>特刊-研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6528?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6528</guid><title>拉曼光谱能够对烘焙食品中的常量营养素进行非侵入性定量评估</title><description>《拉曼光谱杂志》，第 54 卷，第 9 期，第 899-904 页，2023 年 9 月。</description><dc:description>拉曼光谱是一种非侵入性、非破坏性、无标记技术，可用于定量评估烘焙食品（包括面包和饼干）中的碳水化合物、麸质、类胡萝卜素和脂肪。这些信息可用于平衡世界各地数百万人的饮食，并预防肥胖和糖尿病等慢性疾病的发展。摘要 对食物中的大量营养素和微量营养素进行快速、准确的评估可用于平衡全世界数百万人的饮食。这有助于预防肥胖和糖尿病等慢性疾病的发展。可用于揭示食品营养成分信息的现代分析方法具有破坏性且费力。在这项研究中，我们研究了拉曼光谱在对烘焙食品（包括面包和饼干）中的碳水化合物、麸质、类胡萝卜素和脂肪进行非侵入性、非破坏性定量评估方面的潜力。拉曼效应基于非弹性光散射现象。我们的结果表明，拉曼光谱可用于量化烘焙食品中碳水化合物、麸质、类胡萝卜素和脂肪的含量。此外，面包和饼干的独特光谱特征可用于自动识别。这些发现表明，基于拉曼的传感器可用于个性化营养并控制消费食品的质量。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/ba2de585-2a32-4ef8-ac5c-df2ee8cedf57/jrs6528-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;拉曼光谱实现非侵入性烘焙食品中大量营养素的定量评估”/>;&lt;p>;拉曼光谱是一种非侵入性、非破坏性、无标记的技术，可用于烘焙食品中碳水化合物、麸质、类胡萝卜素和脂肪的定量评估食物，包括面包和饼干。这些信息可用于平衡世界各地数百万人的饮食，并预防肥胖和糖尿病等慢性疾病的发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;快速准确地评估食品中的大量营养素和微量营养素可用于平衡全世界数百万人的饮食。这有助于预防肥胖和糖尿病等慢性疾病的发展。可用于揭示食品营养成分信息的现代分析方法具有破坏性且费力。在这项研究中，我们研究了拉曼光谱在对烘焙食品（包括面包和饼干）中的碳水化合物、麸质、类胡萝卜素和脂肪进行非侵入性、非破坏性定量评估方面的潜力。拉曼效应基于非弹性光散射现象。我们的结果表明，拉曼光谱可用于量化烘焙食品中碳水化合物、麸质、类胡萝卜素和脂肪的含量。此外，面包和饼干的独特光谱特征可用于自动识别。这些发现表明，基于拉曼的传感器可用于个性化营养并控制消费食品的质量。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>阿克塞尔·罗德里格兹、德米特里·库洛斯基</dc:creator><category>特刊-研究文章</category><dc:title>拉曼光谱能够对烘焙食品中的常量营养素进行非侵入性定量评估</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1002/jrs.6528</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>拉曼光谱杂志</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1002/jrs.6528</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6528?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>特刊-研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6539?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley：拉曼光谱杂志：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6539</guid><title>合理的设计使基于适配体的传感器能​​够用于小分子的表面增强拉曼检测</title><description>《拉曼光谱杂志》，第 54 卷，第 9 期，第 966-975 页，2023 年 9 月。</description><dc:description>提出了一种基于双适体机制的用于小分子检测的同质 SERS 传感器设计的协议。 Using the well‐defined ATP aptamer as a model system, the effects of hybridization, ACE, and stabilizer length were explored. Abstract Homogeneous surface‐enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) sensors could have a significant impact in environmental analysis. The reagentless mechanism of these sensors makes them capable for in situ analysis and continuous monitoring of environmental pollutants, without having to collect environmental samples for laboratory analysis. Homogeneous SERS sensors take advantage of functional DNA strands on the surface of a SERS‐active particle. These sensors are commonly used for the detection of genomic targets. A clear path to adapt these homogeneous sensors to detect small molecules is to employ aptamer sequences. In particular, the use of duplex aptamer can make these sensors highly adaptable to different target molecules. Although there have been examples of SERS duplex aptamer sensors to detect small molecules, the design rules for this type of sensors have not been elucidated. Without design rules or a design protocol, we would not be able to fully take advantage of the adaptability of this approach to focus on new targets and applications (eg, environmental analysis). Herein, we aim to define a protocol for the design of aptamer‐based homogeneous SERS sensors. First, we demonstrate their nonequilibrium character and the necessary length for the complementary element for the sensors to work. We demonstrate the design protocol on a well‐characterized aptamer sequence for ATP binding and then transfer the knowledge gained on an aptamer for estradiol, a common water contaminant. In this work, we establish the design protocol for a short aptamer (ie, ATP) and analyze the issues and remedies associated with extending this protocol to longer aptamer sequences (eg, E2).</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/b5cf374c-5291-4074-8d33-3cfa10988c77/jrs6539-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rational design enabling aptamer-based sensors for surface-enhanced Raman detection of small molecules&quot;/>; &lt;p>;A protocol is presented for design of homogeneous SERS sensors for small molecule detection based on the duplex aptamer mechanism. Using the well-defined ATP aptamer as a model system, the effects of hybridization, ACE, and stabilizer length were explored. &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Homogeneous surface-enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) sensors could have a significant impact in environmental analysis. The reagentless mechanism of these sensors makes them capable for in situ analysis and continuous monitoring of environmental pollutants, without having to collect environmental samples for laboratory analysis. Homogeneous SERS sensors take advantage of functional DNA strands on the surface of a SERS-active particle. These sensors are commonly used for the detection of genomic targets. A clear path to adapt these homogeneous sensors to detect small molecules is to employ aptamer sequences. In particular, the use of duplex aptamer can make these sensors highly adaptable to different target molecules. Although there have been examples of SERS duplex aptamer sensors to detect small molecules, the design rules for this type of sensors have not been elucidated. Without design rules or a design protocol, we would not be able to fully take advantage of the adaptability of this approach to focus on new targets and applications (eg, environmental analysis). Herein, we aim to define a protocol for the design of aptamer-based homogeneous SERS sensors. First, we demonstrate their nonequilibrium character and the necessary length for the complementary element for the sensors to work. We demonstrate the design protocol on a well-characterized aptamer sequence for ATP binding and then transfer the knowledge gained on an aptamer for estradiol, a common water contaminant. In this work, we establish the design protocol for a short aptamer (ie, ATP) and analyze the issues and remedies associated with extending this protocol to longer aptamer sequences (eg, E2).&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lyndsay N. Kissell, Manisha Sheokand, Pietro Strobbia</dc:creator><category> SPECIAL ISSUE ‐ RESEARCH ARTICLE</category><dc:title> Rational design enabling aptamer‐based sensors for surface‐enhanced Raman detection of small molecules</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1002/jrs.6539</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1002/jrs.6539</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6539?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> SPECIAL ISSUE ‐ RESEARCH ARTICLE</prism:section><prism:volume> 54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6562?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley: Journal of Raman Spectroscopy: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6562</guid><title> Surface‐enhanced Raman imaging of intact cancer cell membrane on a rough aluminum substrate</title><description> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy, Volume 54, Issue 9, Page 940-949, September 2023.</description><dc:description> We performed SERS imaging of intact cell membranes on rough aluminum substrates by comparing them with Si substrates. The comparison of cancer and normal cell membranes revealed different lipid/protein peak ratios in cytoplasm and nucleus‐proximal areas. Abstract The plasma membrane of cancer cells displays differences in lipid and protein composition which distinguish them from healthy cells. Certain molecules have such prominent vibrational characteristics that they can be considered cancer biomarkers. Although Raman spectroscopy is a label‐free non‐invasive method of chemical analysis, it, however, has been limited by weak signals from the membrane compared to the bulk interior of cells. Surface‐enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) on plasmonic gold and silver substrates has previously been used to overcome this limitation. However, the high cost, poor repeatability, and toxicity of these noble metals hinder their practical applications. These challenges may be solved by using different materials and nanostructures. Here, we performed SERS imaging of ovarian cancer cells on rough aluminum substrates and extracted the Raman signals of intact cell membranes by comparing these with the corresponding measurements on Si substrates. We used atomic force microscopy (AFM) for Raman signal calibration. The comparison of cancer and normal cell membranes revealed the different lipid/protein peak ratios in cytoplasm and nucleus‐proximal areas. These Raman signatures of the ovarian cancer can be used as new biomarkers. This method may be extended to other types of cancer biosensing based on aluminum plasmonics.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/93baf5e1-dbbe-43e9-9021-a3391329e241/jrs6562-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;Surface-enhanced Raman imaging of intact cancer cell membrane on a rough aluminum substrate&quot;/>; &lt;p>;We performed SERS imaging of intact cell membranes on rough aluminum substrates by comparing them with Si substrates. The comparison of cancer and normal cell membranes revealed different lipid/protein peak ratios in cytoplasm and nucleus-proximal areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The plasma membrane of cancer cells displays differences in lipid and protein composition which distinguish them from healthy cells. Certain molecules have such prominent vibrational characteristics that they can be considered cancer biomarkers. Although Raman spectroscopy is a label-free non-invasive method of chemical analysis, it, however, has been limited by weak signals from the membrane compared to the bulk interior of cells. Surface-enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) on plasmonic gold and silver substrates has previously been used to overcome this limitation. However, the high cost, poor repeatability, and toxicity of these noble metals hinder their practical applications. These challenges may be solved by using different materials and nanostructures. Here, we performed SERS imaging of ovarian cancer cells on rough aluminum substrates and extracted the Raman signals of intact cell membranes by comparing these with the corresponding measurements on Si substrates. We used atomic force microscopy (AFM) for Raman signal calibration. The comparison of cancer and normal cell membranes revealed the different lipid/protein peak ratios in cytoplasm and nucleus-proximal areas. These Raman signatures of the ovarian cancer can be used as new biomarkers. This method may be extended to other types of cancer biosensing based on aluminum plasmonics.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Sharad Ambardar, Grace Binder, Phat K. Huynh, Dang Nguyen, Hana Hrim, Trung Q. Le, Dmitri V. Voronine</dc:creator><category> SPECIAL ISSUE ‐ RESEARCH ARTICLE</category><dc:title> Surface‐enhanced Raman imaging of intact cancer cell membrane on a rough aluminum substrate</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1002/jrs.6562</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1002/jrs.6562</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6562?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> SPECIAL ISSUE ‐ RESEARCH ARTICLE</prism:section><prism:volume> 54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6571?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley: Journal of Raman Spectroscopy: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6571</guid><title> Surface‐enhanced Raman spectroscopy combined with multivariate analysis for the detection and differentiation of dopamine and DOPAC in cerebrospinal fluid</title><description> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy, Volume 54, Issue 9, Page 917-928, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Surface‐enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) combined with multivariate analysis allows for detection and differentiation of dopamine from its metabolite, DOPAC, at physiologically relevant concentrations and in mixtures in artificial cerebrospinal fluid. Abstract Dopamine (DA) is a vital neurotransmitter for brain functions, including pleasure, memory, motivation, and movement control. Dopaminergic neuron degradation is correlated to neurological disorders such as Parkinson&#39;s disease, and changes in DA concentration are related to mental health disorders. Currently, the gold standard for monitoring DA concentrations in the brain is electrochemistry. However, although electrochemistry has high sensitivity, it has low specificity for molecules with similar molecular structures, such as DA and its metabolites. Here, we demonstrate that surface‐enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS), a vibrational spectroscopy that provides molecule‐specific information with excellent sensitivity, requires small sample sizes/volumes, and is non‐destructive, is optimal for the detection and differentiation of DA and its metabolites. We show that SERS combined with multivariate analysis allows for the detection and differentiation of DA and its metabolites, including 3‐O‐methyldopamine (3‐OMD), homovanillic acid (HVA), 3,4‐dihydroxyphenylacetic acid (DOPAC), and 3‐methoxytyramine (3‐MT) at physiologically relevant concentrations in artificial cerebrospinal fluid (aCSF).</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/74e90f0c-c34c-4a96-8b2b-182a893ee6c9/jrs6571-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;Surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy combined with multivariate analysis for the detection and differentiation of dopamine and DOPAC in cerebrospinal fluid&quot;/>; &lt;p>;Surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) combined with multivariate analysis allows for detection and differentiation of dopamine from its metabolite, DOPAC, at physiologically relevant concentrations and in mixtures in artificial cerebrospinal fluid. &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Dopamine (DA) is a vital neurotransmitter for brain functions, including pleasure, memory, motivation, and movement control. Dopaminergic neuron degradation is correlated to neurological disorders such as Parkinson&#39;s disease, and changes in DA concentration are related to mental health disorders. Currently, the gold standard for monitoring DA concentrations in the brain is electrochemistry. However, although electrochemistry has high sensitivity, it has low specificity for molecules with similar molecular structures, such as DA and its metabolites. Here, we demonstrate that surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS), a vibrational spectroscopy that provides molecule-specific information with excellent sensitivity, requires small sample sizes/volumes, and is non-destructive, is optimal for the detection and differentiation of DA and its metabolites. We show that SERS combined with multivariate analysis allows for the detection and differentiation of DA and its metabolites, including 3-O-methyldopamine (3-OMD), homovanillic acid (HVA), 3,4-dihydroxyphenylacetic acid (DOPAC), and 3-methoxytyramine (3-MT) at physiologically relevant concentrations in artificial cerebrospinal fluid (aCSF).&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Paula A. Pimiento, Natalie E. Dunn, Bhavya Sharma</dc:creator><category> SPECIAL ISSUE ‐ RESEARCH ARTICLE</category><dc:title> Surface‐enhanced Raman spectroscopy combined with multivariate analysis for the detection and differentiation of dopamine and DOPAC in cerebrospinal fluid</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1002/jrs.6571</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1002/jrs.6571</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6571?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> SPECIAL ISSUE ‐ RESEARCH ARTICLE</prism:section><prism:volume> 54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6575?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley: Journal of Raman Spectroscopy: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6575</guid><title> Toward coherent anti‐Stokes Raman scattering‐Raman optical activity for reaction monitoring in organocatalysis: Chiral vibrational signatures of the two atropisomers (R)‐ and (S)‐MOM‐BINOL in solution</title><description> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy, Volume 54, Issue 9, Page 1011-1020, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Coherent anti‐Stokes Raman scattering‐Raman optical activity (CARS‐ROA) spectroscopy reduces acquisition times of spontaneous ROA from several hours to approximately 1 min. We present the first demonstration of heterodyne‐detected CARS‐ROA spectroscopy of chiral molecules (MOM‐BINOL) dissolved in an achiral solvent by using a conventional broadband CARS spectroscopy setup. Abstract Coherent anti‐Stokes Raman scattering‐Raman optical activity (CARS‐ROA) is a coherent version of spontaneous ROA spectroscopy, the latter being a well‐established chirally sensitive vibrational spectroscopic technique. A central major advantage of heterodyne‐detected CARS‐ROA over ROA is the drastic reduction of acquisition times from several hours to approximately 1 min due to the high ratio of the chiral Raman signal relative to the achiral CARS background. Here, we present the first demonstration of heterodyne‐detected CARS‐ROA of chiral molecules dissolved in an achiral solvent by using an experimental setup built from a conventional broadband CARS spectrometer. Specifically, the two atropisomers (R/S) of 2,2′‐Bis(methoxymethoxy)‐1,1′‐binaphthyl, a methoxymethyl (MOM) bis‐protected derivative of 1,1′‐Bi‐2‐naphthol (BINOL), dissolved in the achiral organic solvent dichloromethane (DCM) were characterized by employing ~1 ps, 1 mW of pump pulses and ~60 fs, 10 mW of Stokes pulses within approximately 4‐min acquisition time. MOM‐BINOL is an important precursor for the synthesis of a great variety of many chiral auxiliaries including binaphthyl phosphoric acids, which are an important class of chiral organocatalysts used in asymmetric reactions. Overall, this work is a first step toward kinetic reaction monitoring in organocatalysis by coherent ROA providing the necessary short acquisition times.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/1a09f4a7-2259-4e76-bbb6-a381f17260c1/jrs6575-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;Toward coherent anti-Stokes Raman scattering-Raman optical activity for reaction monitoring in organocatalysis: Chiral vibrational signatures of the two atropisomers (R)- and (S)-MOM-BINOL in solution&quot;/>; &lt;p>;Coherent anti-Stokes Raman scattering-Raman optical activity (CARS-ROA) spectroscopy reduces acquisition times of spontaneous ROA from several hours to approximately 1 min. We present the first demonstration of heterodyne-detected CARS-ROA spectroscopy of chiral molecules (MOM-BINOL) dissolved in an achiral solvent by using a conventional broadband CARS spectroscopy setup. &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Coherent anti-Stokes Raman scattering-Raman optical activity (CARS-ROA) is a coherent version of spontaneous ROA spectroscopy, the latter being a well-established chirally sensitive vibrational spectroscopic technique. A central major advantage of heterodyne-detected CARS-ROA over ROA is the drastic reduction of acquisition times from several hours to approximately 1 min due to the high ratio of the chiral Raman signal relative to the achiral CARS background. Here, we present the first demonstration of heterodyne-detected CARS-ROA of chiral molecules dissolved in an achiral solvent by using an experimental setup built from a conventional broadband CARS spectrometer. Specifically, the two atropisomers (R/S) of 2,2′-Bis(methoxymethoxy)-1,1′-binaphthyl, a methoxymethyl (MOM) bis-protected derivative of 1,1′-Bi-2-naphthol (BINOL), dissolved in the achiral organic solvent dichloromethane (DCM) were characterized by employing ~1 ps, 1 mW of pump pulses and ~60 fs, 10 mW of Stokes pulses within approximately 4-min acquisition time. MOM-BINOL is an important precursor for the synthesis of a great variety of many chiral auxiliaries including binaphthyl phosphoric acids, which are an important class of chiral organocatalysts used in asymmetric reactions. Overall, this work is a first step toward kinetic reaction monitoring in organocatalysis by coherent ROA providing the necessary short acquisition times.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Vikas Kumar, Till Reichenauer, Luca Supovec, Dennis Jansen, Nikolai Brodt, Grzegorz Zając, Agnieszka Domagała, Małgorzata Barańska, Jochen Niemeyer, Sebastian Schlücker</dc:creator><category> RESEARCH ARTICLE</category><dc:title> Toward coherent anti‐Stokes Raman scattering‐Raman optical activity for reaction monitoring in organocatalysis: Chiral vibrational signatures of the two atropisomers (R)‐ and (S)‐MOM‐BINOL in solution</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1002/jrs.6575</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1002/jrs.6575</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6575?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> RESEARCH ARTICLE</prism:section><prism:volume> 54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6577?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 01:18:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T01:18:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10974555?af=R"/> Wiley: Journal of Raman Spectroscopy: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/jrs.6577</guid><title> Determining the twist angle of stacked MoS2 layers using machine learning‐assisted low‐frequency interlayer Raman fingerprints</title><description> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy, Volume 54, Issue 9, Page 1021-1029, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Twisted stacked transition metal dichalcogenides exhibit intriguing properties. In this study, a well‐trained FNN is used to establish a relationship between the interlayer coupling and the twist angle, based on the low‐frequency Raman spectra of twisted bilayer MoS2. DFT and FDM are implemented to determine the interlayer spring constant. By integrating these findings, we successfully construct a twist angle‐dependent linear chain model capable of predicting the breathing mode positions of twisted multilayer MoS2. Abstract The investigation of twisted stacked few‐layer MoS2 has revealed novel electronic, optical, and vibrational properties over an extended period. For the successful integration of twisted stacked few‐layer MoS2 into a wide range of applications, it is crucial to employ a noninvasive, versatile technique for characterizing the layered architecture of these complex structures. In this work, we introduce a machine learning‐assisted low‐frequency Raman spectroscopy method to characterize the twist angle of few‐layer stacked MoS2 samples. A feedforward neural network (FNN) is utilized to analyze the low‐frequency breathing mode as a function of the twist angle. Moreover, using finite difference method (FDM) and density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we show that the low‐frequency Raman spectra of MoS2 are mainly influenced by the effect of the nearest and second nearest layers. A new improved linear chain model (TA‐LCM) with taking the twist angle into the consideration is developed to understand the interlayer breathing modes of stacked few‐layer MoS2. This approach can be extended to other 2D materials systems and provides an intelligent way to investigate naturally stacked and twisted interlayer interactions.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://analyticalsciencejournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/eedd5597-02c5-4843-a9ea-1617c913d0c2/jrs6577-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;Determining the twist angle of stacked MoS2 layers using machine learning-assisted low-frequency interlayer Raman fingerprints&quot;/>; &lt;p>;Twisted stacked transition metal dichalcogenides exhibit intriguing properties. In this study, a well-trained FNN is used to establish a relationship between the interlayer coupling and the twist angle, based on the low-frequency Raman spectra of twisted bilayer MoS2. DFT and FDM are implemented to determine the interlayer spring constant. By integrating these findings, we successfully construct a twist angle-dependent linear chain model capable of predicting the breathing mode positions of twisted multilayer MoS2. &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The investigation of twisted stacked few-layer MoS&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; has revealed novel electronic, optical, and vibrational properties over an extended period. For the successful integration of twisted stacked few-layer MoS&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; into a wide range of applications, it is crucial to employ a noninvasive, versatile technique for characterizing the layered architecture of these complex structures. In this work, we introduce a machine learning-assisted low-frequency Raman spectroscopy method to characterize the twist angle of few-layer stacked MoS&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; samples. A feedforward neural network (FNN) is utilized to analyze the low-frequency breathing mode as a function of the twist angle. Moreover, using finite difference method (FDM) and density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we show that the low-frequency Raman spectra of MoS&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; are mainly influenced by the effect of the nearest and second nearest layers. A new improved linear chain model (TA-LCM) with taking the twist angle into the consideration is developed to understand the interlayer breathing modes of stacked few-layer MoS&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;. This approach can be extended to other 2D materials systems and provides an intelligent way to investigate naturally stacked and twisted interlayer interactions.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jing Tang, Zifan Wang, Qishuo Tan, Jun Cao, Xi Ling</dc:creator><category> RESEARCH ARTICLE</category><dc:title> Determining the twist angle of stacked MoS2 layers using machine learning‐assisted low‐frequency interlayer Raman fingerprints</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1002/jrs.6577</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Journal of Raman Spectroscopy</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1002/jrs.6577</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jrs.6577?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> RESEARCH ARTICLE</prism:section><prism:volume> 54</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item></channel></rss>